<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on Felicia Huang's Website</title><link>http://fnooi.com/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on Felicia Huang's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://fnooi.com/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Assessing the supply and demand of Singapore's attractions using Tripadvisor data</title><link>http://fnooi.com/projects/tripadvisor/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/projects/tripadvisor/</guid><description>Most work on big data for tourism analytics only considers the demand indicators of a city&amp;rsquo;s attractions. This project aims for a novel data-driven analysis that considers both supply and demand indicators when assessing a city’s attractions. Understanding not only what creates demand, but also where supply-demand mismatch exists is crucial for a city to improve its attractiveness.</description></item><item><title>Sensing Community Resilience from COVID-19 Using Social Media</title><link>http://fnooi.com/projects/covid/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/projects/covid/</guid><description>This project discovers social media use and community resilience development during the COVID-19 pandemic in Singapore. Particularly, Singaporean attitudes and sentiments and the roles that social media fulfils in supporting community resilience during a pandemic. The results of the analysis shows that Twitter is not used very often as a tool for grass root collaborative problem-solving, but more often as a tool to coordinate top-down community response and promote connectedness. Geo-tagged data analysis suggests that different regional characteristics do not lead to difference in community resilience efforts across Singapore.</description></item><item><title>AI in Urban Health: Lifelogging</title><link>http://fnooi.com/projects/lifelogging/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/projects/lifelogging/</guid><description>Lifelogging explores older adults' travel pattern and its association with built environment features in real time for 7 days by analysing lifelogging images, locations, and diary. Target participants are older people aged 55 and above from Tampines East, West, North, and Changkat. Student assistants are trained to help with the data collection.
Target Neighbourhood
Narrative Camera Narrative Camera 2 is used to passively collect images of daily activities and environment of the wearer.</description></item><item><title>AI in Urban Health: Participatory GIS Resident Survey</title><link>http://fnooi.com/projects/maptionnaire/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/projects/maptionnaire/</guid><description>A neighbourhood walkability survey was conducted online using a map-based survey tool called Maptionnaire, a participatory GIS survey tool. Unlike a typical survey tool, Maptionnaire has an interactive design that assists participatory urban research and planning. In Maptionnaire, a survey participant can mark a route, or a place, and even an area of interest.
Marking a Place
Marking a Route
Marking an Area</description></item></channel></rss>