<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Felicia Huang's Website</title><link>http://fnooi.com/</link><description>Recent content on Felicia Huang's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://fnooi.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SABRE (Southall and Brent Studies)</title><link>http://fnooi.com/projects/sabre/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/projects/sabre/</guid><description>SABRE (Southall and Brent Studies) is a population based cohort study comparing cardiovascular disease and diabetes between White British people and first-generation migrants of South Asian or African Carribean heritage recruited from West London (Jones, et al. 2020). Data collections include: Baseline (1988-91), 20-year follow up (2008-13), and 25-30 year follow up (2014-18). The SABRE cohort profiles can be viewed in Jones et al. (2020) and Tillin et al. (2012).</description></item><item><title>What I Cook in a Week</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/december2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/december2021/</guid><description>Since relocating to London, cooking has become a part of my daily life. I am in charge of our lunch. In the beginning, I was very ambitious about cooking. I would like to make different food everyday. Eventually, I discovered that it was impossible to do so. I spent too much time in the kitchen. To save time in the kitchen and reduce food waste, I created a list of 7 items to cook, and repeat the recipes every week.</description></item><item><title>What I Cook in a Week</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/en/december2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/en/december2021/</guid><description>Since relocating to London, cooking has become a part of my daily life. I am in charge of our lunch. In the beginning, I was very ambitious about cooking. I would like to make different food everyday. Eventually, I discovered that it was impossible to do so. I spent too much time in the kitchen. To save time in the kitchen and reduce food waste, I created a list of 7 items to cook, and repeat the recipes every week.</description></item><item><title>Что Я Готовлю Каждую Неделю</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/ru/december2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/ru/december2021/</guid><description>После переезда в Лондон кулинария стала важнейшей частью повседневной жизни. Я отвечаю за наш обед. Вначале у меня был очень амбициозный план. Я хотела каждый день готовить новое блюдо. В конце концов я обнаружила, что это невозможно. Я проводила слишком много времени на кухне. Чтобы сэкономить время на кухне и уменьшенить объем отходов продовольствия, я составила список из 7 блюд, которые я буду готовить каждую неделю.
День 1: Рис со Скумбрией И Шпинатом Смешанный рис с маслом чили, скумбрией и шпинатом - это быстрый и вкусный обед, который я готовлю раз в неделю.</description></item><item><title>我做的家常菜</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/zh/december2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/zh/december2021/</guid><description>自从住在伦敦, 做饭变成了我的日常家务之一. 每天我负责做午饭. 一开始, 我对做饭的想象太理想了。 我打算每天无计划地做菜，在网上看什么好吃，就做什么。 这样天天能吃到不一样而且新颖的家常菜。 最后，我发现我花太多时间下厨房，这样下去是不可能的. 为了省时间和减少食物浪费，我列出了我能做的7种菜。 这7种，我每个星期都会重复做。
星期一: 菠菜鲭鱼杂饭 饭烧滚后，加入油辣椒,菠菜,和鲭鱼是一顿又快又好吃的午餐。 我每个星期都会做一次。 菠菜我平时跟着Maangchi的韩式食谱煮的。
菠菜鲭鱼杂饭
星期二: 番茄炒蛋和墨西哥胡椒鱼柳 这饭菜是我做的饭之中谢辽夏最爱吃的。 番茄炒蛋就是中国式的番茄炒蛋。 本来也想做青椒牛柳一起搭配，但是因为这里Waitrose不卖虎皮椒我就以墨西哥胡椒代替虎皮椒。 因为谢辽夏不吃牛羊猪鸡肉我也以鱼代替牛肉。 这样做味道也是一样好吃。 不料，墨西哥胡椒是跟虎皮椒一样辣。 这两个菜我跟着Souped Up Recipe的食谱做的.
番茄炒蛋和墨西哥胡椒鱼柳
星期三: 罗宋汤和和柠檬烤鱼 我个人认为汤是极有营养的食物，必须每个星期喝一次。 如果家里有俄罗斯人什么汤能比得上罗宋汤呢？我说的是俄式，而不是上海香港式的罗宋汤。 罗宋汤非常好喝也非常有营养。 我平时按照Natasha&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen食谱做的, 不过谢辽夏说她的食谱不正确. 他说在俄罗斯一般人会把白菜放在汤里，而且娜塔莎罗宋汤里没有白菜。 可惜，我平时做的罗宋汤口味不一致， 有的时候好喝，有的时候不好喝。 所以，谢辽夏说当一个家里的俄罗斯人从今天起他会负责做罗宋汤。 我反而会做韩式大酱汤和 葱姜清蒸鱼。
罗宋汤和和柠檬烤鱼
星期四: 印尼式豆芽炒虾仁 虽然印尼食物对我来说非常好吃，我很少做印尼菜因为做印尼菜需要各种各样较少见的香料调味料，真的非常麻烦。 不过， 印尼式豆芽炒虾仁 不但好吃而且好做。 我平时也炒几个鸡蛋搭配一起吃。
印尼式豆芽炒虾仁
星期五: 熏三文鱼和柠檬烤龙须菜 这是我7种饭菜里最简单的食物。 只需要买很多超市里会卖的现做熏三文鱼，在烤箱把龙须菜加奶油和柠檬烤一下，跟米饭一起吃。
熏三文鱼和柠檬烤龙须菜
星期六: 担担面 - 比鼎泰丰的好吃 Kimono mom 的担担面真的很好吃.</description></item><item><title>Bagaimana Saya Belajar Mandarin (Part I)</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/id/september2021/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/id/september2021/</guid><description>Saya sangat suka belajar mandarin. Seandainya saja saya punya kesempatan untuk belajar lebih awal, saya yakin saya akan menguasainya lebih baik daripada bahasa inggris. Namun, karena sejumlah represi kultural di Indonesia di masa kecil, saya hanya mendapatkan edukasi mandarin yang cukup bagus di saat saya menginjak umur 20.
Tulisan ini bercerita tentang perjalanan saya belajar mandarin, yang dimulai di saat saya berumur 16 tahun. Saya berharap lewat tulisan ini para pembaca menemukan tips-tips belajar mandarin dan inspirasi untuk terus belajar bahasa.</description></item><item><title>How I Learn Chinese (Part I)</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/en/september2021/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/en/september2021/</guid><description>I enjoy learning chinese. If I had the chance to learn it sooner, I am confident I would have mastered it better than English now. However, due to cultural repression in Indonesia when I was small, I was only able to get a good Chinese education when I was in my 20s.
This essay narrates my chinese learning journey, which began when I was already 16 years old. I hope it will provide some tips and inspiration to adult Chinese learners.</description></item><item><title>How I Learn Chinese (Part I)</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/september2021/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/september2021/</guid><description>I enjoy learning chinese. If I had the chance to learn it sooner, I am confident I would have mastered it better than English now. However, due to cultural repression in Indonesia when I was small, I was only able to get a good Chinese education when I was in my 20s.
This essay narrates my chinese learning journey, which began when I was already 16 years old. I hope it will provide some tips and inspiration to adult Chinese learners.</description></item><item><title>Как Я Изучаю китайский Язык (Часть I)</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/ru/september2021/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/ru/september2021/</guid><description>Мне очень нравится изучать китайский язык. Если бы я его начала изучать раньше, я уверена, что выучила бы его лучше, чем английский сейчас. Однако из-за культурных репрессий в Индонезии, когда я была маленькой, я смогла получить хорошее китайское образование только в возрасте 20 лет.
Этот пост повествует о моем пути изучения китайского языка, которое началось, когда мне было уже 16 лет. Я надеюсь, что это даст читателям несколько полезных советов и вдохновение для изучения китайского языка.</description></item><item><title>Aging</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/en/july2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/en/july2021/</guid><description>My grandmother passed away last month. There were very few things that I knew about her. The space in our relationship was due to physical distance and language differences between us. We resided on diffent Indonesian islands that were far apart. My grandmother spoke Hokkien, a Chinese dialect I didn&amp;rsquo;t speak. Her Indonesian comprehension was modest. We still would have understood each other pretty well, were it not for her poor hearing.</description></item><item><title>Aging</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/july2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/july2021/</guid><description>My grandmother passed away last month. There were very few things that I knew about her. The space in our relationship was due to physical distance and language differences between us. We resided on diffent Indonesian islands that were far apart. My grandmother spoke Hokkien, a Chinese dialect I didn&amp;rsquo;t speak. Her Indonesian comprehension was modest. We still would have understood each other pretty well, were it not for her poor hearing.</description></item><item><title>Menua</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/id/july2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/id/july2021/</guid><description>Nenek saya meninggal bulan lalu. Hal yang saya tahu tentang dia tidak banyak. Jarak dalam hubungan kami terjadi dikarenakan lokasi yang berjauhan dan perbedaan bahasa. Kami tinggal di pulau yang berbeda. Kedua pulau ini jaraknya agak jauh. Nenek saya berbicara bahasa Hokkien, dialek bahasa Cina yang saya tidak kuasai. Pemahaman bahasa Indonesianya tidak begitu mendalam. Kalau bukan karena pendengarannya yang buruk, kami mungkin masih bisa memahami satu sama lain dengan cukup baik.</description></item><item><title>Старение</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/ru/july2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/ru/july2021/</guid><description>Моя бабушка скончалась в прошлом месяце. Я очень мало о ней знала. Из-за физического расстояния и языковых различий мы редко общались. Мы жили на разных индонезийских островах, которые далеко друг от друга. Моя бабушка говорила на хоккиенском диалекте китайского языка, на котором я не говорила. Хотя она чуть-чуть понимала индонезийский, из-за её плохого слуха мы обычно испытывали неловкости в общении.
В память о ней я напишу здесь кое-что из того, что знала о ней.</description></item><item><title>I Passed Russian A1 Exam</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/en/may2021/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/en/may2021/</guid><description>I just passed the A1 level Test of Russian as a Foreign Language (TORFL). Except for writing, I am satisfied with my score. I am not sure why my grade is only 85% for writing. Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s because my story line is a little messy. Two months before the exam, I had to change my teacher. Fortunately, I came upon Polina on instagram (ig: @russianskype). She did an excellent job of preparing me for the exam.</description></item><item><title>I Passed Russian A1 Exam</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/may2021/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/may2021/</guid><description>I just passed the A1 level Test of Russian as a Foreign Language (TORFL). Except for writing, I am satisfied with my score. I am not sure why my grade is only 85% for writing. Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s because my story line is a little messy. Two months before the exam, I had to change my teacher. Fortunately, I came upon Polina on instagram (ig: @russianskype). She did an excellent job of preparing me for the exam.</description></item><item><title>Saya Lulus Ujian Russia Level A1</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/id/may2021/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/id/may2021/</guid><description>Saya baru saja lulus ujian rusia sebagai bahasa international untuk level A1. Level A1 ini adalah level pemula. Kecuali untuk bagian menulis, saya sangat puas dengan nilai yang diperoleh. Saya tidak tahu kenapa nilai menulis saya hanya 85%. Mungkin dikarenakan alur cerita yang agak berantakan.
Dua bulan sebelum ujian, saya harus mencari guru baru. Untungnya, saya menemukan Polina (ig: @russianskype). Dia mempersiapkan saya dengan sangat baik untuk ujian. Kalau bukan karena bimbingannya, saya pasti tidak akan meraih nilai setinggi ini.</description></item><item><title>Я сдала Тест Элементарного Уровня По Русскому Языку (ТРКИ А1)</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/ru/may2021/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/ru/may2021/</guid><description>Я только что сдала тест по русскому языку как иностранному (ТРКИ) «Элементарный уровень». За исключением письма, я удовлетворена результатами. Я не знаю почему у меня только 85% за письмо. Может быть, сюжет написала не так аккуратно. За два месяца до экзаменов мне пришлось сменить преподавателя. К счастью, я нашла Полину (инста: @russianskype). Она хорошо готовила меня к экзамену. Я бы не получила такие высокие баллы, если бы не её уроки.</description></item><item><title>Я Выиграла Блокнот</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/ru/april2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/ru/april2021/</guid><description>В прошлые выходные, на практике рукописного письма в Центре Русского Языка, я выиграла блокнот за самый красивый почерк. Я очень рада :). Я ему найду хорошее применение.
Мой Почерк
Блокнот, Который Выиграла Я</description></item><item><title>I Won a Notebook</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/april2021/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/april2021/</guid><description>Last weekend, in a cursive workshop by the russian language centre, I won a notebook for the best handwriting. I&amp;rsquo;m glad :). I will put this notebook to good use.
My Handwriting
The Notebook I Won. The Cover Reads From Petersburg with Apathy and Indifference</description></item><item><title>I Won a Notebook</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/en/april2021/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/en/april2021/</guid><description>Last weekend, in a cursive workshop by the russian language centre, I won a notebook for the best handwriting. I&amp;rsquo;m glad :). I will put this notebook to good use.
My Handwriting
The Notebook I Won. The Cover Reads From Petersburg with Apathy and Indifference</description></item><item><title>Saya Menang Hadiah Buku Tulis</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/id/april2021/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/id/april2021/</guid><description>Akhir pekan kemarin, di kelas menulis indah yang diselenggarakan oleh Institut Bahasa Rusia, saya memenangkan buku tulis untuk tulisan terbaik. Saya senang sekali :). Tentunya, buku tulis ini akan saya gunakan sebaik-baiknya.
Tulisan Tangan Saya
Buku Catatan yang Saya Menangkan. Di Sampulnya Tertulis Dari Petersburg dengan Tak Acuh dan Tak Peduli</description></item><item><title>我赢了笔记本</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/zh/april2021/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/zh/april2021/</guid><description>上个星期, 在俄语言中心举办的草写入门班我写字写得最漂亮，所以赢得了笔记本. 我非常开心 :). 我将好好利用它.
我的笔迹
我赢得的笔记本. 封面上写着 来自圣彼得堡，带着无动于衷与冷漠</description></item><item><title>我的中文学习旅程 (第一部)</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/zh/september2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/zh/september2021/</guid><description>我非常喜欢学习中文。 要是能趁早最佳年龄段学习，我相信我的中文现在会比我的英语好多了。 可惜，由于印尼过去严厉压制了中华文化，我错过了这个机会，而只能在20多岁的时候接受良好的中文教育。
这篇文章讲述了我从16岁开始到目前坚持学习中文之旅。 我希望它能为学习中文的成年人提供一些实用的学习方式和激发你们的学习动机。
这篇文章分为四个部分，每个部分会叙述我学习中文的不同阶段。 第一部分的内容涵盖了2005-2007年期间，就是我的高中时期。 第二部分发生在2007-2011年，我本科学习的那些年。 第三部分叙述了2007-2013年的学习过程，从我本科毕业后工作，到我开始读博的时候。 最后一部分涵盖了2013-2021年，是我5年的读博时期到现在，保持现有的水平。
第一部分: 高中时期 (2005-2007) 从六十年代开始，印尼政府永久禁制了中华文化表达的权利，包括中文和汉字。 因此，我年轻的时候不像现在一样很容易能找到良好的中文课。 甚至直到如今，印尼中文教育仍存在教育系统问题。 2001年印尼政府解除了对中华文化的禁令，2005年妈妈就安排孩子们学习中文。 她想孩子如果有了中文基础将来被送到新加坡或者台湾留学也会方便一些。
因此，我的中文学习旅程在2005年就开始了。 那时我已经16岁了。 我们每周上一次课。 老师住的地方离我们家不远。 老师用的教材是来自台湾的儿童书。 上课的时候她会让我们读一个故事。 一行一行地读下去。 她先读一行， 我们跟着她读。 新的单词她会让我们在练习本写十几回。 每个星期都如此， 单调乏味，没有变化。 她不教我们正式国语符号的方式比如注音符号或者拼音符号。 我们只是随着她读，随着她写。 在这样不精确的教学模式下我读了两年的中文。 正如我所提到的，在那个时候接受良好的中文教育算是一种奢侈了。
注音符号(Taele &amp;amp; Hammond, 2015)
除此之外，我在高三也上了中文课外活动。 这门课不需要认真去上因为我们获得的成绩根本都不重要。 课本强调的是口语，只教学生们简单的日常沟通，比如“你好吗？”，“我很好“，等等。 老师教我们拼音符号，不过也只是笼统地介绍一下。
由于我学汉语学得晚一点，再加上接受的中文教育质量很低，所以上大学的时候我的中文水平只达到了基本级(HSK2或者可以算是CEFR A1级)。</description></item><item><title>老苦</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/zh/july2021/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/zh/july2021/</guid><description>我的奶奶上个月去世了。 我对她了解得很少。 我们之间的距离是由位置距离和语言不同所造成的。 我和奶奶住在印尼不同的岛屿。这两个岛屿之间的距离相当远。她讲的是福建话，而小的时候的我只能说印尼话。 奶奶说印尼话说得马马虎虎。 要是她听力很好，我们也许还能顺利地沟通。 可惜，她听力不好加上印尼话不标准常常让我们交流非常尴尬。
为了纪念她，我会在这里记录一下我所知道她的二三事。 奶奶年轻时是邻里最漂亮的姑娘之一。 空闲时间里奶奶喜欢修剪植物，或者在市场上讨价还价。 奶奶也很喜欢去中国旅游。 当她身体很好的时候，每年她都会去中国广西。 她为什么去，是否在那边还有亲戚，去了哪个城市我就不知道了。
我的奶奶
在过去的两年里，老年痴呆症导致了她慢慢地失去记忆和身体机能。 每次我妈妈对我们说明奶奶下降的健康，我都会想起佛法所描述的老苦， 正如14世纪藏族学者龙钦巴尊者所说：
有一天你身体失去能力的时候到了。 此时，你站着坐着走动都困难。 感官衰退 - 眼睛混浊不透明，听力模糊不清； 你的记忆力及思考能力也慢慢衰退。 你的幸福感一样慢慢下降， 你的头脑也常常不清爽，容易疲倦。 当你的神经系统和活力减弱时，你变得胆小和敏感， 像一个幼儿。 因为你的火气和精神衰退， 所以你很容易受到多种伤病的困扰。 结果，你成了身边人的负担。 你说你想死， 但其实，你恐惧死亡，这加剧了你精神上的痛苦。
她去世之后， 我请求印度的一家我过去四年到现在一直支助的尼姑庵为她祈祷。 愿她获得安乐往生。
潦倒晚年</description></item><item><title>我通过了俄语能力基本级测验(TORFL A1)</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/zh/may2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/zh/may2021/</guid><description>我刚通过了俄语能力基本级测验. 这等级应该跟汉语拼音水平考试第2级差不多。除了写作之外，我对我的分数都很满意。 我不明白为什么写作只考了85分，可能是因为故事的情节写得有点乱吧。 考试两个月前, 我需要换老师. 很幸运我找到了波琳娜小姐 （你可以在 ins @russianskype 找到她）。非常感谢她帮助我为获得 好成绩做的充分准备。 如果没有她的指导，我不会拿到这么好的成绩。
我的分数
我发现考试的考题不是完全随机生成的，考题是为新加坡俄语言中心的学生专门准备的。 随机试题的文本，比如下面书内容的文本，会包括各种各样的题目，从最简单的日常沟通到关于历史展览，稍微有点复杂的文本。 考试里文本的题目，是大致围绕着俄语言中心的教材而设计的，因为我不是跟俄语言中心学习，所以我必须为各种可能出现的题目做好充足准备。这样， 我的词汇量得到扩大，考试显得更容易。
随机样本试题
现在我想跟你们分享关于考试对我来说最难的一部分：口试。口试在网上进行。我们的考官是圣彼得堡国立大学的老师。 我的考官叫奥列格。
口试分为三部分。 第一和第二部分需要我们当场做出回应，就没有准备的时间。为了让口试考得很好， 我跟我的老师要了很多口试样本，然后跟我的男朋友多多练习。我的男朋友建议我要从容自若地回答，最好说话之前花一点时间想想答案。
不过因为太紧张，我还是急着说话，因而语法也说错了一些。 还好因为我已经做好充分准备，错误不多。 口试完成时，奥列格跟我说我的发音非常好，所以必须继续学俄语。他的话深深鼓励了我。</description></item></channel></rss>