<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Felicia Huang's Website</title><link>http://fnooi.com/</link><description>Recent content on Felicia Huang's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://fnooi.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Assessing the supply and demand of Singapore's attractions using Tripadvisor data</title><link>http://fnooi.com/projects/tripadvisor/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/projects/tripadvisor/</guid><description>Most work on big data for tourism analytics only considers the demand indicators of a city&amp;rsquo;s attractions. This project aims for a novel data-driven analysis that considers both supply and demand indicators when assessing a city’s attractions. Understanding not only what creates demand, but also where supply-demand mismatch exists is crucial for a city to improve its attractiveness.</description></item><item><title>Sensing Community Resilience from COVID-19 Using Social Media</title><link>http://fnooi.com/projects/covid/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/projects/covid/</guid><description>This project discovers social media use and community resilience development during the COVID-19 pandemic in Singapore. Particularly, Singaporean attitudes and sentiments and the roles that social media fulfils in supporting community resilience during a pandemic. The results of the analysis shows that Twitter is not used very often as a tool for grass root collaborative problem-solving, but more often as a tool to coordinate top-down community response and promote connectedness. Geo-tagged data analysis suggests that different regional characteristics do not lead to difference in community resilience efforts across Singapore.</description></item><item><title>AI in Urban Health: Lifelogging</title><link>http://fnooi.com/projects/lifelogging/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/projects/lifelogging/</guid><description>This project employs lifelogging to understand neighbourhood walkability of the Tampines Town in Singapore. Lifelogging is a method that explores travel pattern and its association with built environment features in real time. Three lifelogging data is used: lifelogging images, locations, and diary. Different tools are used to capture this data: a small wearable camera, a gps tracker, and a travel diary.
Photo:newatlas.com. Wearable Camera</description></item><item><title>AI in Urban Health: Participatory GIS Resident Survey</title><link>http://fnooi.com/projects/maptionnaire/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/projects/maptionnaire/</guid><description>This project uses a Participatory GIS Resident Survey tool, Maptionnaire, to understand neighbourhood walkability of the Tampines Town in Singapore. Unlike a typical survey tool, Participatory GIS survey incorporates GIS functionality into the survey questions, enabling participants to mark a route, a place, or an area of interest.
Marking a Place
Marking a Route
Marking an Area</description></item><item><title>I Passed Russian A1 Exam</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/en/may2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/en/may2021/</guid><description>I just passed the A1 level Test of Russian as a Foreign Language (TORFL). Except for writing, I am satisfied with my score. I am not sure why my grade is only 85% for writing. Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s because my story line is a little messy. Two months before the exam, I had to change my teacher. Fortunately, I came upon Polina on instagram (ig: @russianskype). She did an excellent job of preparing me for the exam.</description></item><item><title>I Passed Russian A1 Exam</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/may2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/may2021/</guid><description>I just passed the A1 level Test of Russian as a Foreign Language (TORFL). Except for writing, I am satisfied with my score. I am not sure why my grade is only 85% for writing. Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s because my story line is a little messy. Two months before the exam, I had to change my teacher. Fortunately, I came upon Polina on instagram (ig: @russianskype). She did an excellent job of preparing me for the exam.</description></item><item><title>Saya Lulus Ujian Russia Level A1</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/id/may2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/id/may2021/</guid><description>Saya baru saja lulus ujian rusia sebagai bahasa international untuk level A1. Level A1 ini adalah level pemula. Kecuali untuk bagian menulis, saya sangat puas dengan nilai yang diperoleh. Saya tidak tahu kenapa nilai menulis saya hanya 85%. Mungkin dikarenakan alur cerita yang agak berantakan.
Dua bulan sebelum ujian, saya harus mencari guru baru. Untungnya, saya menemukan Polina (ig: @russianskype). Dia mempersiapkan saya dengan sangat baik untuk ujian. Kalau bukan karena bimbingannya, saya pasti tidak akan meraih nilai setinggi ini.</description></item><item><title>Я сдала Тест Элементарного Уровня По Русскому Языку (ТРКИ А1)</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/ru/may2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/ru/may2021/</guid><description>Я только что сдала тест по русскому языку как иностранному (ТРКИ) «Элементарный уровень». За исключением письма, я удовлетворена результатами. Я не знаю почему у меня только 85% за письмо. Может быть, сюжет написала не так аккуратно. За два месяца до экзаменов, мне пришлось сменить преподаватель. К счастью, я нашла Полину (инста: @russianskype). Она хорошо готовила меня к экзамену. Я бы не получила такие высокие баллы, если бы не её уроки.</description></item><item><title>我通过了俄语能力基本级测验(TORFL A1)</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/zh/may2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/zh/may2021/</guid><description>我刚通过了俄语能力基本级测验. 这等级应该跟汉语拼音水平考试第2级差不多。除了写作之外，我对我的分数都很满意。 我不明白为什么写作只考了85分，可能是因为故事的情节写得有点乱吧。 考试两个月前, 我需要换老师. 很幸运我找到了波琳娜小姐 （你可以在 ins @russianskype 找到她）。非常感谢她帮助我为获得 好成绩做的充分准备。 如果没有她的指导，我不会拿到这么好的成绩。
我的分数
我发现考试的考题不是完全随机生成的，考题是为新加坡俄语言中心的学生专门准备的。 随机试题的文本，比如下面书内容的文本，会包括各种各样的题目，从最简单的日常沟通到关于历史展览，稍微有点复杂的文本。 考试里文本的题目，是大致围绕着俄语言中心的教材而设计的，因为我不是跟俄语言中心学习，所以我必须为各种可能出现的题目做好充足准备。这样， 我的词汇量得到扩大，考试显得更容易。
随机样本试题
现在我想跟你们分享关于考试对我来说最难的一部分：口试。口试在网上进行。我们的考官是圣彼得堡国立大学的老师。 我的考官叫奥列格。
口试分为三部分。 第一和第二部分需要我们当场做出回应，就没有准备的时间。为了让口试考得很好， 我跟我的老师要了很多口试样本，然后跟我的男朋友多多练习。我的男朋友建议我要从容自若地回答，最好说话之前花一点时间想想答案。
不过因为太紧张，我还是急着说话，因而语法也说错了一些。 还好因为我已经做好充分准备，错误不多。 口试完成时，奥列格跟我说我的发音非常好，所以必须继续学俄语。他的话深深鼓励了我。</description></item><item><title>I Won a Notebook</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/april2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/april2021/</guid><description>Last weekend, in a cursive workshop by the russian language centre, I won a notebook for the best handwriting. I&amp;rsquo;m glad :). I will put this notebook to good use.
My Handwriting
The Notebook I Won. The Cover Reads From Petersburg with Apathy and Indifference</description></item><item><title>I Won a Notebook</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/en/april2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/en/april2021/</guid><description>Last weekend, in a cursive workshop by the russian language centre, I won a notebook for the best handwriting. I&amp;rsquo;m glad :). I will put this notebook to good use.
My Handwriting
The Notebook I Won. The Cover Reads From Petersburg with Apathy and Indifference</description></item><item><title>Saya Menang Hadiah Buku Tulis</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/id/april2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/id/april2021/</guid><description>Akhir pekan kemarin, di kelas menulis indah yang diselenggarakan oleh Institut Bahasa Rusia, saya memenangkan buku tulis untuk tulisan terbaik. Saya senang sekali :). Tentunya, buku tulis ini akan saya gunakan sebaik-baiknya.
Tulisan Tangan Saya
Buku Catatan yang Saya Menangkan. Di Sampulnya Tertulis Dari Petersburg dengan Tak Acuh dan Tak Peduli</description></item><item><title>我赢了笔记本</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/zh/april2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/zh/april2021/</guid><description>上个星期, 在俄语言中心举办的草写入门班我写字写得最漂亮，所以赢得了笔记本. 我非常开心 :). 我将好好利用它.
我的笔迹
我赢得的笔记本. 封面上写着 来自圣彼得堡，带着无动于衷与冷漠</description></item><item><title>Я Выиграла Блокнот</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/ru/april2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/ru/april2021/</guid><description>В прошлые выходные, на практике рукописного письма в Центре Русского Языка, я выиграла блокнот за самый красивый почерк. Я очень рада :). Я ему найду хорошее применение.
Мой Почерк
Блокнот, Который Выиграла Я</description></item></channel></rss>