<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Felicia Huang's Website</title><link>http://fnooi.com/</link><description>Recent content on Felicia Huang's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://fnooi.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Assessing the supply and demand of Singapore's attractions using Tripadvisor data</title><link>http://fnooi.com/projects/tripadvisor/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/projects/tripadvisor/</guid><description>Most work on big data for tourism analytics only considers the demand indicators of a city&amp;rsquo;s attractions. This project aims for a novel data-driven analysis that considers both supply and demand indicators when assessing a city’s attractions. Understanding not only what creates demand, but also where supply-demand mismatch exists is crucial for a city to improve its attractiveness.</description></item><item><title>Sensing Community Resilience from COVID-19 Using Social Media</title><link>http://fnooi.com/projects/covid/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/projects/covid/</guid><description>This project discovers social media use and community resilience development during the COVID-19 pandemic in Singapore. Particularly, Singaporean attitudes and sentiments and the roles that social media fulfils in supporting community resilience during a pandemic. The results of the analysis shows that Twitter is not used very often as a tool for grass root collaborative problem-solving, but more often as a tool to coordinate top-down community response and promote connectedness. Geo-tagged data analysis suggests that different regional characteristics do not lead to difference in community resilience efforts across Singapore.</description></item><item><title>AI in Urban Health: Lifelogging</title><link>http://fnooi.com/projects/lifelogging/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/projects/lifelogging/</guid><description>This project employs lifelogging to understand neighbourhood walkability of the Tampines Town in Singapore. Lifelogging is a method that explores travel pattern and its association with built environment features in real time. Three lifelogging data is used: lifelogging images, locations, and diary. Different tools are used to capture this data: a small wearable camera, a gps tracker, and a travel diary.
Photo:newatlas.com. Wearable Camera</description></item><item><title>AI in Urban Health: Participatory GIS Resident Survey</title><link>http://fnooi.com/projects/maptionnaire/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/projects/maptionnaire/</guid><description>This project uses a Participatory GIS Resident Survey tool, Maptionnaire, to understand neighbourhood walkability of the Tampines Town in Singapore. Unlike a typical survey tool, Participatory GIS survey incorporates GIS functionality into the survey questions, enabling participants to mark a route, a place, or an area of interest.
Marking a Place
Marking a Route
Marking an Area</description></item><item><title>I Won a Notebook</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/april2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/april2021/</guid><description>Last weekend, in a cursive workshop by the russian language centre, I won a notebook for the best handwriting. I&amp;rsquo;m glad :). I will put this notebook to good use.
My Handwriting
The Notebook I Won. The Cover Reads From Petersburg with Apathy and Indifference</description></item><item><title>I Won a Notebook</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/en/april2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/en/april2021/</guid><description>Last weekend, in a cursive workshop by the russian language centre, I won a notebook for the best handwriting. I&amp;rsquo;m glad :). I will put this notebook to good use.
My Handwriting
The Notebook I Won. The Cover Reads From Petersburg with Apathy and Indifference</description></item><item><title>Saya Menang Hadiah Buku Tulis</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/id/april2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/id/april2021/</guid><description>Akhir pekan kemarin, di kelas menulis indah yang diselenggarakan oleh Institut Bahasa Rusia, saya memenangkan buku tulis untuk tulisan terbaik. Saya senang sekali :). Tentunya, buku tulis ini akan saya gunakan sebaik-baiknya.
Tulisan Tangan Saya
Buku Catatan yang Saya Menangkan. Di Sampulnya Tertulis Dari Petersburg dengan Tak Acuh dan Tak Peduli</description></item><item><title>我赢了笔记本</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/zh/april2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/zh/april2021/</guid><description>上个星期, 在俄语言中心进行的草写作坊, 因为字写得很漂亮，我赢得了笔记本. 我非常开心 :). 我将好好利用它.
我的笔迹
我赢得的笔记本. 封面上写着 来自圣彼得堡，带着无动于衷与冷漠</description></item><item><title>Я Выиграла Блокнот</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/ru/april2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/ru/april2021/</guid><description>В прошлые выходные, на практике рукописного письма в Центре Русского Языка, я выиграла блокнот за самый красивый почерк. Я очень рада :). Я ему найду хорошее применение.
Мой Почерк
Блокнот, Который Выиграла Я</description></item></channel></rss>