<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tenang on Felicia Huang's Website</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/en/</link><description>Recent content in Tenang on Felicia Huang's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://fnooi.com/tenang/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Aging</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/en/july2021/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/en/july2021/</guid><description>My grandmother passed away last month. There were very few things that I knew about her. The space in our relationship was due to physical distance and language differences between us. We resided on diffent Indonesian islands that were far apart. My grandmother spoke Hokkien, a Chinese dialect I didn&amp;rsquo;t speak. Her Indonesian comprehension was modest. We still would have understood each other pretty well, were it not for her poor hearing.</description></item><item><title>I Passed Russian A1 Exam</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/en/may2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/en/may2021/</guid><description>I just passed the A1 level Test of Russian as a Foreign Language (TORFL). Except for writing, I am satisfied with my score. I am not sure why my grade is only 85% for writing. Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s because my story line is a little messy. Two months before the exam, I had to change my teacher. Fortunately, I came upon Polina on instagram (ig: @russianskype). She did an excellent job of preparing me for the exam.</description></item><item><title>I Won a Notebook</title><link>http://fnooi.com/tenang/en/april2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://fnooi.com/tenang/en/april2021/</guid><description>Last weekend, in a cursive workshop by the russian language centre, I won a notebook for the best handwriting. I&amp;rsquo;m glad :). I will put this notebook to good use.
My Handwriting
The Notebook I Won. The Cover Reads From Petersburg with Apathy and Indifference</description></item></channel></rss>